<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Raspberry Pi on James Horton</title>
    <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/tags/raspberry-pi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Raspberry Pi on James Horton</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jjhorton.co.uk/tags/raspberry-pi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Automatically panellization of Kicad PCB&#39;s with github Actions</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/kicad-github-panels/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/kicad-github-panels/</guid>
      <description>As part of my PCB design workflow I use kibot to process my PCB&amp;rsquo;s and generate the Gerber files I need for PCB manufacture, but sometimes to make better use of the of the PCB size I want to create panels that are the minimum size I need to pay for with JLCPCB who I frequently use to make these boards. Another problem I have found when doing respins of boards that have problems or errors, is keeping track of different versions, while i have tried in the past to keep up with a version on the board this hasn&amp;rsquo;t always worked out, so for these boards I wanted to add reference to the git version used to generate the files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading the christmas countdown with GPS</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/chrismas_gps_countdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/chrismas_gps_countdown/</guid>
      <description>The countdown timer that I created last year, which used my custom RP2040 Pmod board with the PMod Severn Segment Display I had also created, was in need of an upgrade. The main aim of this project was to replace the Raspberry Pi Zero that provided the time data to what was just a display made of my custom hardware, and turn it into something that can run automonously, by getting that time data from a GPS reveiver.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a GPS PMod Board</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/gps_pmod_board/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/gps_pmod_board/</guid>
      <description>I have been looking to put together a GPS board for a while, as I had a few ideas for upgrading a project with realtime time information, and a few things that I could try out if I had location or time data, as well as an accurate timing pulse source. While there are actually plenty of options for just buying a pre-made PMod module, I decided I would be better of giving it a go myself as I wanted a few of them and that could make it cheaper to build my own if I needed a few.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started IKEA Vindriktning in Home Assistant with Pico W</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/ikea-air_quality-sensor/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/ikea-air_quality-sensor/</guid>
      <description>The IKEA Vindriktning is an air quality sensor sold for just £13, that makes use of a PM1006 sensor inside to detect particle matter in the air. Normally the readins from the sensor are displayed on one of 3 LED&amp;rsquo;s on the front of the unit, but here we are looking to collect this data and add it into Home Assistant .
There are a large number of posts and instructions avalible online for modifying the IKEA Vindriktning or removing the PM1006 sensor and building a Home Assistant integrated sensor using an ECP32 module.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christmas Countdown</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/christmascountdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/christmascountdown/</guid>
      <description>Christmas Countdown on the Whiteboard Using my 7 segment display I wanted to build a Christmas countdown, this was just going to use the PMod Display that I had around, and then run from one of the RP2040 boards that I built earlier this year. As I wanted a count down that is frequently updating, I chose to use the countdown in seconds, as this for the month of December easily fits within the seven segments available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seven Segment Display PMod Board</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/sevensegmentdisp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/sevensegmentdisp/</guid>
      <description>Ive always wanted to build a severn segment display, there is something about the old school style displays that it is hard to beat to display random numerical data like in the movies.
The 7 Segment display that I decided to use, comes with 4 digits per display, and I was looking to combine two per PMod Board, with 8 LED per segment, we don&amp;rsquo;t have enough pins to be able to control them all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RP2040 PMod PCB</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/rp2040_pmod/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/rp2040_pmod/</guid>
      <description>Having perviously built myself a Pico PMod Board around the Raspberry Pi Pico, I wanted to take this to the next level, and build myself a few boards from scratch. So once the orders went live for the RP2040 microcontroller a few months ago, I ordered some, and then did nothing with them for a while.
Like many people, I seem to end up with more ideas than time and it took me a little while to get around to this one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pico PMod breakout PCB</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/picopmod/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/picopmod/</guid>
      <description>Pico on a Breadboard After picking up a few Raspberry Pi Pico&amp;rsquo;s, I was looking for a use for them and I decided to hook up a few of the PMod boards I have from playing around with FPGA. This PMod boards all use the same pinout, of 12 pins, which consists of 8 I/O pins, two 3.3V, and two GND connections on a two row 2.54mm header. I have a few kicking around from a more complex ones, down to a simple 8 DIP switch and a 7 segment display.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bring a Raspberry Pi Cluster Back to Life</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/piclusterreborn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/piclusterreborn/</guid>
      <description>The raspberry pi cluster was built several years ago for some projects I was doing at the time, and experimenting with parallel computing. While the little raspberry pi&amp;rsquo;s were never going to keep up with a proper PC, they were great for experimenting with the principles of parallel computing, being it making use of the multiple CPU cores on each device or trying to spread the calculation over multiple raspberry pi&amp;rsquo;s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Octave on my Raspberry Pi Cluster</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/octave-on-my-raspberry-pi-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/octave-on-my-raspberry-pi-cluster/</guid>
      <description>The main aim of building my Raspberry Pi Cluster was so that I could run octave code on it, now I&amp;rsquo;m not expecting to break any records, but ideally I want some performance. The best way I found to do this was with the parallel&amp;rsquo;s package.
With octave and the parallels package installed on each of the Raspberry Pi 2&amp;rsquo;s in the cluster, I setup SSH so that no passwords are required between the nodes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Over clocking my Raspberry Pi cluster</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/over-clocking-my-raspberry-pi-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/over-clocking-my-raspberry-pi-cluster/</guid>
      <description>With my newly created raspberry pi cluster being made out of the Raspberry Pi 2, I don&amp;rsquo;t want it to lag to far behind the freshly announced Raspberry Pi 3. To try and keep up with the new hardware without replacing all of my Pi&amp;rsquo;s I devices it was worth a go at overclocking them.
Overlooking my Pi&amp;rsquo;s should allow them to work a bit quicker, but it will reduce power efficient and increase the tempurature that the cluster runs at.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Raspberry Pi Cluster</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/building-a-raspberry-pi-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/building-a-raspberry-pi-cluster/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had a long standing interest in Parallel Processing, and then a few months ago I came across Octave and its parallel package. Octave is very similar to MATLAB that I use every day, and for the most part basic MATLAB code works out of the box in Octave.
I used this as the perfect excuse to build myself a mini-cluster computer&amp;hellip;
The mini cluster needed to be cheep, so I based it on the raspberry pi.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
