<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>white water on James Horton</title>
        <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/tags/white-water/</link>
        <description>Recent content in white water on James Horton</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-uk</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jjhorton.co.uk/tags/white-water/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Last minute trip to Dartmoor</title>
        <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/last-minute-trip-to-dartmoor/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/last-minute-trip-to-dartmoor/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/DartmoorLM_exeter.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Last minute trip to Dartmoor" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The original plan for the weekend was for a BVCC club trip up to
Yorkshire to sample some of the white water that is on offer up North,
but it wasn’t too be. Not to be put of by the lack of water up north
arrangements were for a few of us to head south instead, and down to
Dartmoor. With the rooms booked in a local Travelodge on the Thursday
night, and rain forecast it was looking like a good shout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Packing up all my gear ready for &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/kayaking?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#kayaking&lt;/a&gt; in dartmoor &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/ReadyForTheWeekend?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#ReadyForTheWeekend&lt;/a&gt; https://t.co/CmxfZ74zGm&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; James Horton (@JamesjHorton) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/JamesjHorton/status/423926717179510784?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;January 16, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the Saturday morning every meet in the little chef next door for some
breakfast and Wifi signal so we could check the gauges and hut out a
river. Unfortunately there hadn’t been as much rain as was hoped, and
the gauges were still showing on the low side, but we decided to head to
the middle Tavy which wasn’t far for the Travelodge we were staying at
in Oakhampton and go for a look at least. The section in town looked
like it was running, so we left my car at the bottom and headed upto the
get on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While all the travel faffing and driving had been going on the heavens
had opened, little did we realize it but these little storms would keep
going all day. With the river levels on the rise we were of, during the
time we were on the water the level went from scrape/low on the
rainchasers website to high.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The middle Tavy is a rewarding run, with its more or less continuous
grade 3 water all the way down, most of which can be inspected from the
boat, giving a good fun run. Most of the group had never run the river
before, and those of us that had, couldn’t remember it, so gave a good
opportunity to practice those river leading skills on some interesting
water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After running the river, and popping into Tavistock town center to get
some food we went down to have a look at the Upper section of the River
Plym. The section was running at a high level, but we only went for a
look this evening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Lots of water for &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/kayaking?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#kayaking&lt;/a&gt; in dartmoor this weekend &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/winning?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#winning&lt;/a&gt; https://t.co/f6iGnmflEs&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; James Horton (@JamesjHorton) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/JamesjHorton/status/424616078971764736?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;January 18, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After heading back to our accommodation, we spent an hour consulting
which pub to visit for food asking the opinions of many including
google, and some locals only to decide to spend the evening at the pub
over the road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Is de-icing the inside of the windscreen normal? &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/cold?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#cold&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://t.co/ActeWWkmCd&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/ActeWWkmCd&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; James Horton (@JamesjHorton) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/JamesjHorton/status/424833896237514752?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;January 19, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again over night there hadn’t been much rain, and by the time we got up
on Sunday morning everything was covered in frost. With little rain
forecast for the rest of the day we consulted the rain gauges, and
settled on heading out and paddling the Lower Section of the Plym.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lower section of the Plym, was of similar difficulty to the section
of the Tavy we paddled on the Saturday with a grading of 3/4. The run
starts of at it most difficult, with some of the rapids hard to see
down, but then settles down into a nice run. At the level we ran it the
group thought that a bit more water would have been beneficial, with a
few of the rapids felling particularly rocky. All in all it was a good
run, that we completed quickly as it was only a few km long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;The question is after paddling the Plym this morning should we now paddle Pots or go to the pub &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/fb?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#fb&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://t.co/kdnpwyfPKJ&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/kdnpwyfPKJ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; James Horton (@JamesjHorton) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/JamesjHorton/status/424921542665846784?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;January 19, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After we decided to Pots Weir in Exeter to have a look at the play
feature there, but we bravely decided to head into the pub there, as the
weir was running very high after all the rainfall they have seen down
that was in the last few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Popping into Wales for a paddle</title>
        <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/popping-into-wales-for-a-paddle/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/popping-into-wales-for-a-paddle/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/2014_south_wales.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Popping into Wales for a paddle" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;With most of the country suffering with storms and rain over the
Christmas period one of the few groups of people who were looking out
the window all excited were the kayakers…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;I think the ford maybe a bit to deep today, time to find another way around &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/flood?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#flood&lt;/a&gt; http://t.co/FylGGkijTS&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; James Horton (@JamesjHorton) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/JamesjHorton/status/418769624868859904?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;January 2, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately unable to get out paddling until after the new year we hit
the road on the Friday after new year to meet up in Swansea ready for a
bit of paddling. Despite the huge amount of water that seemed to be
flooding most of the field I saw on my journey into south wales the
river levels on Saturday morning seemed disappointingly low. Despite
this we headed of out of Swansea to the River Tawe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;A good day &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/kayaking?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#kayaking&lt;/a&gt; today in South Wales, managed to find some water for once! http://t.co/EDCg4JCZL7&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; James Horton (@JamesjHorton) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/JamesjHorton/status/419518659380273153?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;January 4, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The river could have done with a bit more water, we meet another group
at the get on, who had decided it was too low for them and were heading
elsewhere in search of water. We decided it was worth a run, so hopped
on and went for a paddle. The river is made up of some fun rapids,
including a good slide and a decent ledge drop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After running the river we went for a walk up another local river that
wasn&amp;rsquo;t running, which had amazingly good phone reception considering how
remote it seemed!  The river showed some great potential, but with trees
stuck across the majority of the river and it being in need of some more
water it wasn’t going to be happening this weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Not sure where we are but it has 3G signal &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/lost?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#lost&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/wales?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#wales&lt;/a&gt; http://t.co/b0xUPIqwlI&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; James Horton (@JamesjHorton) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/JamesjHorton/status/419488264731373568?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;January 4, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all this we retired back to Swansea for some Champaign out of
mugs, before heading of down to our natural habitat… the pub.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>36 Hours in North Wales</title>
        <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/36-hours-in-north-wales/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/36-hours-in-north-wales/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/DSCF2940.JPG" alt="Featured image of post 36 Hours in North Wales" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the lack of paddling while up in scotland the opportunity came for
to spend the weekend up in north wales with &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.bromleycanoeclub.co.uk/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Bromley Canoe
Club&lt;/a&gt;. Unfortunately yet again it
was looking like there would still be a complete lack of water, but
knowing that at least the River Dee would be running I packed my
Playboat and in the early hours of Saturday Morning headed to the
&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.tyddynbychan.co.uk/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;bunkhouse&lt;/a&gt; they were staying at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/DSCF2890.JPG&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bunkhouse was one I stay at regularly, so regularly with the
different paddling groups that lydia the owner wanted to check which
name they knew me by &amp;ldquo;Potter&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Harry&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;James&amp;rdquo; as well as find out
the details of what had happened to Richard&amp;rsquo;s van while up in scotland.
After much faffing and breakfast we headed to the River Dee, which in
the past I have only paddled in low or very high water, but this time it
was a good level, providing some good play waves and serpents tail
almost managed to back loop me, but I managed to keep my head dry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the Trywern not releasing for the weekend and only a bit of rain
for the night, we were expecting to end up back on the Dee again
tomorrow, so I chose not to run town fall instead opting for one of the
many river left lines down under the bridge, to get back to the car a
bit quicker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So came Sunday morning, and it turned out there had been a fairly
large amount of rain over night. It soon became apparent as we were
traveling around that the rivers were high, as we saw groups paddling
though fields alongside the A5! After looking around for a bit we
settled on running the River Conwy, which made me wish I had packed the
River Runner - as the playboat (Dagger Kingpin) was hardly the ideal
boat to be takling this in, especially as we watched the gauge under the
bridge disappear bellow the water line&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/DSCF2934.JPG&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/DSCF2937.JPG&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The river turned out to be good fun, the river had become big
and bouncy which was great fun in the playboat, testing my ability to
stay upright all the way along. The stoppers produced some entertaining
moments, which combined with the eddy lines ensuring I saw a lot of the
sky on my way down the river. We had a few swims in the group, which
produced some challenging boat chases especially in my little playboat
searching for eddies behind trees and rocks that are normally on the
bank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/DSCF2940.JPG&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all it turned out to be a great weekend, maybe next time I&amp;rsquo;ll
think to pack my river runner just incase it rains in wales!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Week Two in Scotland</title>
        <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/week-two-in-scotland/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/week-two-in-scotland/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/544146_10151527924663011_1555724195_n.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Week Two in Scotland" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Well week 2 wasn&amp;rsquo;t much different to week 1, with there still being no water in Scotland. As a result much of the time was spent walking and sight seeing rather than kayaking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/DSCF2758.JPG&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We paddled the River Awe, which allowed us to see some interesting signs, hide Richards boat in the middle of the river and experience a bit of white water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/DSCF2696.JPG&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/DSCF2697.JPG&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily the River Garry was releasing again this week, which gave me opportunity to get my head wet, as well as practice my air brace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/482860_10151593707651079_1922721987_n.jpg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photo by &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/aoifestrahan&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Aoife Strahan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/544146_10151527924663011_1555724195_n.jpg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;
Photo By Phil Porter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from that there was just much driving, walking, sight seeing and general relaxing at the spa - Certainly not the 2 weeks away that I had
planned in my mind but a relaxing holiday instead. Lets just hope for some more water next time!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Week one in Scotland</title>
        <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/week-one-in-scotland/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/week-one-in-scotland/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/DSCF2219.JPG" alt="Featured image of post Week one in Scotland" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This last week I have been in the Fort William area with the university
of Surrey Canoe Club, for a week of white water paddling. Despite Fort
William being known for giving reliable white water we managed to pick
the time of year were there was no rain, and only snow!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/IMG_0363.JPG&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The journey up to Fort William had been a battle, with the country being
hit by large snowfall and high wind warning along almost the entire
route, but all the vehicles managed to make it along the A82 without
incident, unlike many cars that were seen along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/DSCF2633.JPG&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We stayed near the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.inchree.co.uk/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Inchree Chalets&lt;/a&gt;, not far
outside fort william, with 3 of them rented for the group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sunday&#34;&gt;Sunday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/DSCF2219.JPG&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite being warned of the low water, we were hopeful that at least
some of the rivers would run, but it was today that we realized just how
little water was going to be about, unless we got some more rain. The
first river we tried was the Spean Gorge Section, which should be
runnable in most levels, but as we soon found out most levels doesn’t
include as low as this. Many sections that we would have expected to
find features were none existent, and some not even passable, with the
portage becoming a way of life. This is also before you coincided the
long flat water scrape back to the vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;monday&#34;&gt;Monday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/DSCF2238.JPG&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the lack of water the day before, instead of heading of kayaking
most of the group went for a walk to look at the Inchree Falls that were
located close to the bunkhouse. With much of the group going for an
explore around the falls which have been run a handful of times,
followed by a number of people scaling a nearby hill, to see the view,
and the snow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tuesday&#34;&gt;Tuesday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/DSCF2287.JPG&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the group not managing to get on the water the day before, we
decided to give the Arkaig a go, this river runs between 2 lochs, but
even this does not guarantee there will be any water. The river was
found to be runnable, if not completely different to how it would be
normally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/DSCF2300.JPG&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the group ran the main rapid multiple times, making use of the
water and the short walk back up. At the get off to the river is a
bridge going over the loch, which many people may have jumped off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/DSCF2375.JPG&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;wednesday&#34;&gt;Wednesday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not for the first time this week we found the lack of water an issue, so a number of the group decide to go and make use of another form of white water up in Glencoe, and go skiing instead. With the remainder of the
group taking a walk up the River Nevis in the afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;thursday&#34;&gt;Thursday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today we had some guaranteed water in the form of the first dam release
of the year on the River Garry. This made a welcome break from the rest
of the week were the group were able to paddle without scraping along
the rocks like previous rivers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/DSCF2489.JPG&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we arrived at the get on the river was quiet and the water was
still rising, but it didn’t take long for the river level to have risen
and the car park to have been filled. The river had large numbers of
groups, making the most of the release to get out paddling with a number
of university groups around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/DSCF2465.JPG&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following on from a good few runs we heading to the Moriston to see what
the levels looked like up there, but the lack of water was easy to see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;friday&#34;&gt;Friday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/DSCF2525.JPG&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the first day of the week the river level in the Etive had picked up enough to make it worth a fun, so the group decided to jump on for a run while they could. Triple Falls had enough water to fall over, along with a scrap through bits in between that the group was able to run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/DSCF2620.JPG&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All this was enough to ensure that people got some photos of them
falling over right angle falls before the final day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now the university group head backs to Guildford, but i’ve got another
week of waiting for the rain gods to provide some water&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Lake District</title>
        <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/lake-district/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/lake-district/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/DSCF2173.JPG" alt="Featured image of post Lake District" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last weekend I joined &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.bvcc.org.uk/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Blackwater Valley Canoe
Club&lt;/a&gt; for a trip unto the Lake District, for
most of the people going they were heading up on Thursday making the
most of the February half term. Unfortunately we don’t get half terms at
university, so I had to wait until my final lecture had finished at 5pm
on Friday to hit the road and head north, which as it turns out is a
very long way! Even only taking only one stop along the way it still
took almost 6 and a half hours including the time spent in traffic, not
getting to the
&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://dentonhouse-keswick.co.uk/pages/accommodation.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;bunkhouse&lt;/a&gt;until
11:59PM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/DSCF2164.JPG&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the early start on Saturday we headed north to do the River Eden,
which as with the rest of the rivers up north this weekend was low. The
river was mainly flat, with large sections of flat water paddling, but
the final rapid and pub at the end made up for this. This river was also
the first outing of my new paddles picked up only a few days ago on the
way to an interview. Being a low run it was hardly ideal, and there are
already scratches on the paddles! After this it was back to the
bunkhouse and off into town to look though the many outdoor shops, 
trying to avoid spending money on lost of shiny new toys, but I managed
to get away only buying a new sling and crab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/DSCF2173.JPG&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the Sunday we paddled the River Kent, the section was much shorter
than what we had paddled on The River Eden, as well as being much more
action packed. The rapids were all located quickly together, together
with a few small drops which made for a great run. The odd thing about
this paddling is that we were done much earlier than normal (Before
Midday), but with the long run home we decided to head of home early
after a bit of Dry suit conga (Photo bellow by &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.fluidfocus.co.uk/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Mike
Hamilton&lt;/a&gt;), knowing that we had many hours
of driving ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://jjhorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/P1020358.jpg&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://jjhorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/P1020358.jpg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;P1020358&#34;
	
	
&gt;{.aligncenter
.size-full .wp-image-424 width=&amp;ldquo;640px&amp;rdquo;
height=&amp;ldquo;480px&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Full BVCC Trip report available
&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.bvcc.org.uk/2/forum/viewtopic.php?f=36&amp;amp;t=829&amp;amp;p=3006#p3006&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>A cold weekend in Dartmoor</title>
        <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/a-cold-weekend-in-dartmoor/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/a-cold-weekend-in-dartmoor/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/DSCF1930.JPG" alt="Featured image of post A cold weekend in Dartmoor" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last weekend was spent in one of the places that I have kayaked the
most, dartmoor. Although trips here normally revole around the river
dart, normally on the loop and upper this time we
found ourselves looking further afield. Paddling with 4 friends from uni
on the same weekend that the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://gene17.com/riverssource/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;River
Source&lt;/a&gt; event the aim was to try and
avoid the country park as best we could.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/DSCF1897.JPG&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our accommodation for the weekend was a &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.yha.org.uk/barn/great-hound-tor-camping-barn&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;YHA camping
barn&lt;/a&gt; which is
basic at best, very different to the usual bunkhouses with beds and
central heating. This was a barn with some areas for sleeping, a gas
camping stove, and a wood burn and that is it. The main advantage of
this was that it was dirt cheap, helping keep the cost fo the weekend
down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Saturday morning we were joined by Rich who for reasons we never
really worked out had driven down in the small hours of the morning, and
we paddled the Walkham. The river Walkham both me and Richard had
paddled before, but for the others this was a new river. The levels
were reasonably good, although in places we could have done with a few
more cm&amp;rsquo;s. One surprise that we did find was a log stuck just bellow the
slot, which was a point of concern, but didn&amp;rsquo;t cause us any issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/DSCF1919.JPG&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had originally hoped we would be able to do 2 rivers on the saturday
morning, and although we were up bright and early it didn&amp;rsquo;t work out,
allowing us only 3 hours until sunset as we reached our get off we
headed for a local cafe for some warmth, before heading on to the pub in
Princetown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/DSCF1930.JPG&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sunday morning didn&amp;rsquo;t really go to plan, after going to sleep a bit
later than planned as we were sat around the warm fire, followed by the
phone we were using as a alarm running out of battery we didn&amp;rsquo;t even
wake up until 8:30. The group headed of to see if the River Erme had
enough water to run, and although it was on the low side decided it
would be runnable. Richard and myself had been lucky enough to have
paddled it in the summer when it was higher and decided to give it a
miss with Richard joining some of my mates from &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.bromleycanoeclub.co.uk/index.php&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Bromley Canoe
Club&lt;/a&gt; who had been down for
the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://gene17.com/riverssource/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;River Source Weekend&lt;/a&gt; that was
taking place at the country park.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to head to a local cafe, and then take a walk up the path to
get a few photos of the group heading down the river. We then hit the
road home with a short diversion into Exeter to &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.millontheexe.co.uk/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Mill on the
Exe&lt;/a&gt; to see the Pots Weir and have a
meal before heading back to guildford.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>A weekend on the Barle</title>
        <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/a-weekend-on-the-barle/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/a-weekend-on-the-barle/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/2012_Barle_3.jpg" alt="Featured image of post A weekend on the Barle" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the 4th year in a row a trip down the River Barle marks the start
of my winter white water session here in the Uk. The river Barle being
my second white water kayaking trip seems like a long time ago,
paddling for survival in one of the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://uniscanoe.co.uk&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;University of Surrey Canoe
Club&lt;/a&gt; boats on my second trip since starting
university. Now 4 years on I find myself drifting down the river in my
play boat drifting along enjoying the sights. This year I joined
&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://BVCC.org.uk&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Blackwater Valley Canoe Club&lt;/a&gt; for the trip, along
with 5 other ex-Surrey students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/2012_Barle_1.jpg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After spending the morning in university on Friday the quickest packed
I&amp;rsquo;d managed to do in a long time, we hit the road and headed for
exmoor down the A303, a road that I normally get to know quiet well
over the winter months. For the weekend we were staying at &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://exmoorhostel.co.uk&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Dulverton
Residential Center&lt;/a&gt;, somewhere we have all
stayed a number of times before. The hostel has to be one of the most
confusing layouts that I have experienced in a bunkhouse, with a
basement kitchen, and 2 upstairs floors of bedrooms connected by what
seems like a maze of staircases. That said it is one of the most
comfortable bunkhouses we stay in each year, combined with central
heating which is well worth it given the freezing temperatures that
we&amp;rsquo;re forecast each night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/2012_Barle_2.jpg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This weekend there seemed to be a lack of water in the river, just
enough to float down the river but continuous rock dodging especially
on the Saturday where we paddled from Tar Steps to Dulverton. The
paddling on the Sunday was much better, aided possibly from some rain
on Saturday night where we continued down the river to exe bridge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/2012_Barle_3.jpg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Hurley for the day</title>
        <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/hurley-for-the-day/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/hurley-for-the-day/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/2012_Hurley_1.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Hurley for the day" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;After nearly 4 years of paddling I&amp;rsquo;ve finally got around to getting
some qualifications, the first one a few weeks ago was the FSRT
(Foundation Safety and Rescue) Training. The training was run by Simon
from backwater valley canoe club and was good fun, even though last
year I did my advanced white water safety and rescue.
We did the course on the river Thames, nearly Hurley weir and to break
the day up we couldn&amp;rsquo;t say no to a quick play on the weir which was on
2 gates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/2012_Hurley_2.jpg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The journey home begins</title>
        <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/the-journey-home-begins/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/the-journey-home-begins/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/LastDayinScotland.JPG" alt="Featured image of post The journey home begins" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;With everyone up and awake early, they knew they had a long journey
ahead, with the chalets clean everyone hit the road for home, well not
quiet everyone. I headed in the opposite direction, with my sights set of
the Nevis Range. This was another chance to have a run at some of the
routes I had done on Wednesday. This time I only managed to do
the Championship Red Route, having not fully recovered from yesterdays
kayaking, with it taking me longer this time than it did on Wednesday.
So with the weather not looking very good I hit the road and started on
the journey home, the difference begin I was taking my time unlike the
journey there, so stopped off a few times to take pictures and watch a
random man plan the bagpipes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/LastDayinScotland.JPG&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Only a few mountains stand between me and my hoteltonight&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After all these stops I made it to my home for the night, a Travelodge
in Glasgow, swapping the view off the highlands to one of Type
45 Destroyers that are being finished off on the other side of the
river.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The final day in the kayak</title>
        <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/the-final-day-in-the-kayak/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/the-final-day-in-the-kayak/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/DSCF1027.JPG" alt="Featured image of post The final day in the kayak" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Well we all knew this days was coming, the final day of kayaking in
Scotland. Having know this was coming we had planned an epic day of
kayaking, all starting with the earliest alarm of the week at 7am, ready
to hit the road at 8am with the satnav&amp;rsquo;s aimed at Glen Etive&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason for this early start would all soon before clear, that being
the longest and hardest walk in that I have ever undertaken, which make
the walk in on the Garry seem small in comparison. This river is a
tributary to the River Etive, the Allt a&amp;rsquo; Chaorainn, This river as
described by richard &amp;ldquo;is gravity feed, water is only required for
lubrication&amp;rdquo;, and I can&amp;rsquo;t say he isn&amp;rsquo;t wrong. With the early start and
the long hike, when we were stood in the middle of nowhere at 10am,
ready to hit the water I was hoping he was right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/DSCF0989.JPG&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the 5 off use who took our boats along for the long hike the effort
easily justified, taking us down huge rock slides, narrow slots while
testing our ability to dodge rocks. As we went down the river we
were accompanied by Rhiannon, Ian and Emma who had been entrusted  with
the cameras, so hopefully the photos should appear over the next few
days of the trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/ScotlandSlide2012.jpg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Me making my way down Pinball Machine&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After arriving at the bottom of the river we packed the boats into the
back of richards Van, and prepared to head off to do what everyone had
been waiting for, the Etive. For many people including myself this was
the opportunity to run some of the biggest drops we have ever done, as
well as get some new Facebook profile pictures. We started of at tripple
falls  (which was much more impressive than the other tripple falls I
had done on the Dart Loop!), watching richard to a run first to give use
who had never done it before an idea off the line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/DSCF0998.JPG&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then set up safety, and the first guys and girls where off with
Rhiannon following Richard down, she made it successfully down the first
drop, only to go over at the bottom. Following a failed attempt at
rolling, then taking a swim beween the first and second drop. She was
then followed by Polina, who powered down both the first and second
drop successfully and even survived a few iffy moments in the eddy
bellow the drop. Bob, followed the girls down, making a point of saying
hello to Mike on the way down although we don&amp;rsquo;t think it was
intentional! With the 4 off them back in the boats they made there way
down the final drop with Polina taking a swim at the bottom. Myself and
Zoe, then joined richard to a quick run from top to bottom, with
Richards only run to be caught on camera he messed up. Not to mention
Zoe needing Richards Help after ending up against the wall at the bottom
of the 3rd drop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/DSCF1027.JPG&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the bottom, most people pilled into the cars and headed off to right
angle falls, with Richard, Zoe, Bob and myself paddling down the river
to meet them, while Mike headed down with his camera kit to capture the
action as we paddled down. With both me and Bob having never paddled the
river we were relying on Richard&amp;rsquo;s and Zoe&amp;rsquo;s memory, Richard took the
lead, for another amazing section of river. With each feature known not
my its name but by who ran it, and who/what got broken there when the
university group paddled it last year. The quick pace off the run made
it really enjoyable, with quick inspections off the features, and the
small number of us allowing for a quick run of the river. The run was
uneventful, apart from Zoe&amp;rsquo;s swim at letter box, for which richard wins
the award of most useless throw line for (all will be explained when the
video appears).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were soon down at Right Angle Falls, and ready to do the biggest
waterfall that many off us had ever done. The girls who had done tripple
falls  took the option for Richard to launch them from directly above
the drop, both completing it successfully, albeit with a bit of swimming
after. The time came for my run, and I seemed to go for the option off
keep paddling and then air brace (something I seem to have a habit
of), disappearing underwater for sometime, but resurfacing upright,
meaning I managed to stay upright for the whole trip, without the need
for a single roll!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/RightAngle2012.jpg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Me heading over right angle falls&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the time we were are Right Angle Falls every single weather
Scotland could trow at us had come though; Sun, Rain, Wind, Hail and
Snow, but Nothing seemed to be able to wipe the smile of peoples faces,
it was a great way to end the weeks paddling, now time to pack up ready
for most people to hit the road home tomorrow, while I&amp;rsquo;ll be off
Mountain Biking.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Falls of Lora</title>
        <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/falls-of-lora/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/falls-of-lora/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/FallsofLora.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Falls of Lora" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today we were up early, for the second day of paddling we were going to do something a bit stupid, the falls of lora.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Fall of Lora are formed as the tide changes, and lasts for a few hours, with the height of the tide determining how and which waves form. Today happened to be one off the biggest of the year and we happened to be there, an opportunity to be missed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Me and Richard were the only ones stupid/brave enough to give it a go, joining the large numbers of locals, and university groups that had turned out to see what it is all about. Getting there nice and early to watch it form we then hoped of the water at around 11:30, with the
wave still building. Richard was at home on the wave enjoying a good surf and play of the wave, unlike me. I was struggling with the huge eddie line and still not feeling at home in my playboat, as a result I only had a few goes which I didn&amp;rsquo;t achieve much in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we were here the rest of the group went on to paddle the River Awe, but we decided rather than chasing them the local cafe along with an hour in the spa was a better idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/IMG_8556.JPG&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>First day in Scotland</title>
        <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/first-day-in-scotland/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/first-day-in-scotland/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/FirstDayScotland.jpg" alt="Featured image of post First day in Scotland" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the long drive yesterday, today we hit the first river off the
trip the River Loche. Although you would think the rivers would have had
enough of driving following the 100&amp;rsquo;s of miles covered yesterday,
everyone seemed to enough the rally stage like road which takes you to
the get on, the single track making a nice change to the motorway and A
roads everyone had been traveling on yesterday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/DSCF0816.JPG&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This river was a gentle start to the trip, with the river being mostly
flat. It was also our first opportunity to paddle as a group, and see
how everyones paddling was, as well as get comfortable in our boats. The
river has only one small feature, but more than enough to keep everyone
entertains in the small feature that is half way down the river.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Packed and ready to hit the road to Scotland</title>
        <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/packed-and-ready-to-hit-the-road-to-scotland/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/packed-and-ready-to-hit-the-road-to-scotland/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Well the time has come for my first trip to scotland, and its been a
long time coming. Most people who take up kayaking tend to end up
kayaking as many places at home before the head overseas, but for me the
sunshine in the alps has ment I&amp;rsquo;ve never headed north beyond Yorkshire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what to take to scotland? Well the big boats in, thats a given but
I&amp;rsquo;m also taking the Playboat, I don&amp;rsquo;t know why at the moment but I&amp;rsquo;m
sure that it&amp;rsquo;ll hit the water at some point over the 10 days. All thats
assuming there is any water, but based on what i&amp;rsquo;ve head there was only
snow up there the other day so the mountain bike is also having another
outing - which is amazing given it hadn&amp;rsquo;t let the house all year before
the start off this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along with all the normal rubbish I take on these trips means my car is
very full, but soon it will be on its 400 mile journey to this place
they call &amp;ldquo;scotland&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://jjhorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2012/04/carkayak.jpg&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://jjhorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2012/04/carkayak.jpg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;image0&#34;
	
	
&gt;{.aligncenter
.size-full .wp-image-131 width=&amp;ldquo;640px&amp;rdquo;
height=&amp;ldquo;480px&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
