<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>white water on James Horton</title>
    <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/tags/white-water/</link>
    <description>Recent content in white water on James Horton</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jjhorton.co.uk/tags/white-water/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Last minute trip to Dartmoor</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/last-minute-trip-to-dartmoor/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/last-minute-trip-to-dartmoor/</guid>
      <description>The original plan for the weekend was for a BVCC club trip up to Yorkshire to sample some of the white water that is on offer up North, but it wasn’t too be. Not to be put of by the lack of water up north arrangements were for a few of us to head south instead, and down to Dartmoor. With the rooms booked in a local Travelodge on the Thursday night, and rain forecast it was looking like a good shout.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Popping into Wales for a paddle</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/popping-into-wales-for-a-paddle/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/popping-into-wales-for-a-paddle/</guid>
      <description>With most of the country suffering with storms and rain over the Christmas period one of the few groups of people who were looking out the window all excited were the kayakers…
I think the ford maybe a bit to deep today, time to find another way around #flood pic.twitter.com/FylGGkijTS
&amp;mdash; James Horton (@JamesjHorton) January 2, 2014  Unfortunately unable to get out paddling until after the new year we hit the road on the Friday after new year to meet up in Swansea ready for a bit of paddling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>36 Hours in North Wales</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/36-hours-in-north-wales/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/36-hours-in-north-wales/</guid>
      <description>After the lack of paddling while up in scotland the opportunity came for to spend the weekend up in north wales with Bromley Canoe Club. Unfortunately yet again it was looking like there would still be a complete lack of water, but knowing that at least the River Dee would be running I packed my Playboat and in the early hours of Saturday Morning headed to the bunkhouse they were staying at.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week Two in Scotland</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/week-two-in-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/week-two-in-scotland/</guid>
      <description>Well week 2 wasn&amp;rsquo;t much different to week 1, with there still being no water in Scotland. As a result much of the time was spent walking and sight seeing rather than kayaking.
 
We paddled the River Awe, which allowed us to see some interesting signs, hide Richards boat in the middle of the river and experience a bit of white water.
 
 
Luckily the River Garry was releasing again this week, which gave me opportunity to get my head wet, as well as practice my air brace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week one in Scotland</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/week-one-in-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/week-one-in-scotland/</guid>
      <description>This last week I have been in the Fort William area with the university of Surrey Canoe Club, for a week of white water paddling. Despite Fort William being known for giving reliable white water we managed to pick the time of year were there was no rain, and only snow!
 
The journey up to Fort William had been a battle, with the country being hit by large snowfall and high wind warning along almost the entire route, but all the vehicles managed to make it along the A82 without incident, unlike many cars that were seen along the way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lake District</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/lake-district/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/lake-district/</guid>
      <description>Last weekend I joined Blackwater Valley Canoe Club for a trip unto the Lake District, for most of the people going they were heading up on Thursday making the most of the February half term. Unfortunately we don’t get half terms at university, so I had to wait until my final lecture had finished at 5pm on Friday to hit the road and head north, which as it turns out is a very long way!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A cold weekend in Dartmoor</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/a-cold-weekend-in-dartmoor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/a-cold-weekend-in-dartmoor/</guid>
      <description>Last weekend was spent in one of the places that I have kayaked the most, dartmoor. Although trips here normally revole around the river dart, normally on the loop and upper this time we found ourselves looking further afield. Paddling with 4 friends from uni on the same weekend that the River Source event the aim was to try and avoid the country park as best we could.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A weekend on the Barle</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/a-weekend-on-the-barle/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/a-weekend-on-the-barle/</guid>
      <description>For the 4th year in a row a trip down the River Barle marks the start of my winter white water session here in the Uk. The river Barle being my second white water kayaking trip seems like a long time ago, paddling for survival in one of the University of Surrey Canoe Club boats on my second trip since starting university. Now 4 years on I find myself drifting down the river in my play boat drifting along enjoying the sights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hurley for the day</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/hurley-for-the-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/hurley-for-the-day/</guid>
      <description>After nearly 4 years of paddling I&amp;rsquo;ve finally got around to getting some qualifications, the first one a few weeks ago was the FSRT (Foundation Safety and Rescue) Training. The training was run by Simon from backwater valley canoe club and was good fun, even though last year I did my advanced white water safety and rescue. We did the course on the river Thames, nearly Hurley weir and to break the day up we couldn&amp;rsquo;t say no to a quick play on the weir which was on 2 gates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The journey home begins</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/the-journey-home-begins/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/the-journey-home-begins/</guid>
      <description>With everyone up and awake early, they knew they had a long journey ahead, with the chalets clean everyone hit the road for home, well not quiet everyone. I headed in the opposite direction, with my sights set of the Nevis Range. This was another chance to have a run at some of the routes I had done on Wednesday. This time I only managed to do the Championship Red Route, having not fully recovered from yesterdays kayaking, with it taking me longer this time than it did on Wednesday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The final day in the kayak</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/the-final-day-in-the-kayak/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/the-final-day-in-the-kayak/</guid>
      <description>Well we all knew this days was coming, the final day of kayaking in Scotland. Having know this was coming we had planned an epic day of kayaking, all starting with the earliest alarm of the week at 7am, ready to hit the road at 8am with the satnav&amp;rsquo;s aimed at Glen Etive
The reason for this early start would all soon before clear, that being the longest and hardest walk in that I have ever undertaken, which make the walk in on the Garry seem small in comparison.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Falls of Lora</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/falls-of-lora/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/falls-of-lora/</guid>
      <description>Today we were up early, for the second day of paddling we were going to do something a bit stupid, the falls of lora.
The Fall of Lora are formed as the tide changes, and lasts for a few hours, with the height of the tide determining how and which waves form. Today happened to be one off the biggest of the year and we happened to be there, an opportunity to be missed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First day in Scotland</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/first-day-in-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/first-day-in-scotland/</guid>
      <description>After the long drive yesterday, today we hit the first river off the trip the River Loche. Although you would think the rivers would have had enough of driving following the 100&amp;rsquo;s of miles covered yesterday, everyone seemed to enough the rally stage like road which takes you to the get on, the single track making a nice change to the motorway and A roads everyone had been traveling on yesterday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Packed and ready to hit the road to Scotland</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/packed-and-ready-to-hit-the-road-to-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/packed-and-ready-to-hit-the-road-to-scotland/</guid>
      <description>Well the time has come for my first trip to scotland, and its been a long time coming. Most people who take up kayaking tend to end up kayaking as many places at home before the head overseas, but for me the sunshine in the alps has ment I&amp;rsquo;ve never headed north beyond Yorkshire.
So what to take to scotland? Well the big boats in, thats a given but I&amp;rsquo;m also taking the Playboat, I don&amp;rsquo;t know why at the moment but I&amp;rsquo;m sure that it&amp;rsquo;ll hit the water at some point over the 10 days.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
