<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>white water on James Horton</title>
    <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/tags/white-water/</link>
    <description>Recent content in white water on James Horton</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jjhorton.co.uk/tags/white-water/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Last minute trip to Dartmoor</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/last-minute-trip-to-dartmoor/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/last-minute-trip-to-dartmoor/</guid>
      <description>The original plan for the weekend was for a BVCC club trip up to Yorkshire to sample some of the white water that is on offer up North, but it wasn’t too be. Not to be put of by the lack of water up north arrangements were for a few of us to head south instead, and down to Dartmoor. With the rooms booked in a local Travelodge on the Thursday night, and rain forecast it was looking like a good shout.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week Two in Scotland</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/week-two-in-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/week-two-in-scotland/</guid>
      <description>Well week 2 wasn&amp;rsquo;t much different to week 1, with there still being no water in Scotland. As a result much of the time was spent walking and sight seeing rather than kayaking.
 
We paddled the River Awe, which allowed us to see some interesting signs, hide Richards boat in the middle of the river and experience a bit of white water.
 
 
Luckily the River Garry was releasing again this week, which gave me opportunity to get my head wet, as well as practice my air brace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week one in Scotland</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/week-one-in-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/week-one-in-scotland/</guid>
      <description>This last week I have been in the Fort William area with the university of Surrey Canoe Club, for a week of white water paddling. Despite Fort William being known for giving reliable white water we managed to pick the time of year were there was no rain, and only snow!
 
The journey up to Fort William had been a battle, with the country being hit by large snowfall and high wind warning along almost the entire route, but all the vehicles managed to make it along the A82 without incident, unlike many cars that were seen along the way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A cold weekend in Dartmoor</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/a-cold-weekend-in-dartmoor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/a-cold-weekend-in-dartmoor/</guid>
      <description>Last weekend was spent in one of the places that I have kayaked the most, dartmoor. Although trips here normally revole around the river dart, normally on the loop and upper this time we found ourselves looking further afield. Paddling with 4 friends from uni on the same weekend that the River Source event the aim was to try and avoid the country park as best we could.
Our accommodation for the weekend was a YHA camping barn which is basic at best, very different to the usual bunkhouses with beds and central heating.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The final day in the kayak</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/the-final-day-in-the-kayak/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/the-final-day-in-the-kayak/</guid>
      <description>Well we all knew this days was coming, the final day of kayaking in Scotland. Having know this was coming we had planned an epic day of kayaking, all starting with the earliest alarm of the week at 7am, ready to hit the road at 8am with the satnav&amp;rsquo;s aimed at Glen Etive
The reason for this early start would all soon before clear, that being the longest and hardest walk in that I have ever undertaken, which make the walk in on the Garry seem small in comparison.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Falls of Lora</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/falls-of-lora/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/falls-of-lora/</guid>
      <description>Today we were up early, for the second day of paddling we were going to do something a bit stupid, the falls of lora.
The Fall of Lora are formed as the tide changes, and lasts for a few hours, with the height of the tide determining how and which waves form. Today happened to be one off the biggest of the year and we happened to be there, an opportunity to be missed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First day in Scotland</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/first-day-in-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/first-day-in-scotland/</guid>
      <description>After the long drive yesterday, today we hit the first river off the trip the River Loche. Although you would think the rivers would have had enough of driving following the 100&amp;rsquo;s of miles covered yesterday, everyone seemed to enough the rally stage like road which takes you to the get on, the single track making a nice change to the motorway and A roads everyone had been traveling on yesterday.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
