<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PMod on James Horton</title>
    <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/tags/pmod/</link>
    <description>Recent content in PMod on James Horton</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jjhorton.co.uk/tags/pmod/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Infrared Sensor with an LED Matrix</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/ir_hub75/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/ir_hub75/</guid>
      <description>Having picked up a couple of LED Matrix&amp;rsquo;s from aliexpress that I thought should finally be put to some good use, having perviously made up some IR Thermal camera PMods I thought it would be a great idea to hook them up together, and have a nice big display with the array from these sensors scaled up.
The hardware that is needed mostly relies on what I had already built, mainly the RP2040 PMod Board and the PMod IR Camera, but there is the need for a board to interface between the HUB75 display and the RP2040 PMod board.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading the christmas countdown with GPS</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/chrismas_gps_countdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/chrismas_gps_countdown/</guid>
      <description>The countdown timer that I created last year, which used my custom RP2040 Pmod board with the PMod Severn Segment Display I had also created, was in need of an upgrade. The main aim of this project was to replace the Raspberry Pi Zero that provided the time data to what was just a display made of my custom hardware, and turn it into something that can run automonously, by getting that time data from a GPS reveiver.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a GPS PMod Board</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/gps_pmod_board/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/gps_pmod_board/</guid>
      <description>I have been looking to put together a GPS board for a while, as I had a few ideas for upgrading a project with realtime time information, and a few things that I could try out if I had location or time data, as well as an accurate timing pulse source. While there are actually plenty of options for just buying a pre-made PMod module, I decided I would be better of giving it a go myself as I wanted a few of them and that could make it cheaper to build my own if I needed a few.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christmas Countdown</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/christmascountdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/christmascountdown/</guid>
      <description>Christmas Countdown on the Whiteboard Using my 7 segment display I wanted to build a Christmas countdown, this was just going to use the PMod Display that I had around, and then run from one of the RP2040 boards that I built earlier this year. As I wanted a count down that is frequently updating, I chose to use the countdown in seconds, as this for the month of December easily fits within the seven segments available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seven Segment Display PMod Board</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/sevensegmentdisp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/sevensegmentdisp/</guid>
      <description>Ive always wanted to build a severn segment display, there is something about the old school style displays that it is hard to beat to display random numerical data like in the movies.
The 7 Segment display that I decided to use, comes with 4 digits per display, and I was looking to combine two per PMod Board, with 8 LED per segment, we don&amp;rsquo;t have enough pins to be able to control them all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infrared Sensors and Neopixel screen</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/infraredsensorneopixel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/infraredsensorneopixel/</guid>
      <description>After perviously building a PMod Infrared Sensor board, that was perviously streaming data ovesr the serial link from the RP2040 PMod board to a PC which was using Python to display the data. The next step is to look at using a screen to display the data from the infrared Sensor.
The screen that I looked to use is a custom board based on using the Neopixel LED&amp;rsquo;s that I have previously used with the RP2040 board, this allows a simple way to display the data, the screen which is also a 8x8 grid the same resolution as the sensor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RP2040 PMod PCB</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/rp2040_pmod/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/rp2040_pmod/</guid>
      <description>Having perviously built myself a Pico PMod Board around the Raspberry Pi Pico, I wanted to take this to the next level, and build myself a few boards from scratch. So once the orders went live for the RP2040 microcontroller a few months ago, I ordered some, and then did nothing with them for a while.
Like many people, I seem to end up with more ideas than time and it took me a little while to get around to this one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PMod 8x8 Infrared Sensor</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/infraredsensorpmod/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/infraredsensorpmod/</guid>
      <description>After seeing a post on twitter where someone was experimenting with the AMG8834 sensor, and I wanted to give it a go. This sensor can be purchased preassembled on breakout boards, ready to drop into a breadboard and build a system around.
While I could build something around these breakout boards, I decided to take a different route and have a go at building one of my own boards. for the connector I wanted to use a PMod, as this would allow me to use the board with both my Raspberry Pi Pico Boards that I just made, as well as the iceBreaker FPGA board I already own, and maybe in the future I may have a go with getting it working with my Zynq based Cora Z7 board.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pico PMod breakout PCB</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/picopmod/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/picopmod/</guid>
      <description>Pico on a Breadboard After picking up a few Raspberry Pi Pico&amp;rsquo;s, I was looking for a use for them and I decided to hook up a few of the PMod boards I have from playing around with FPGA. This PMod boards all use the same pinout, of 12 pins, which consists of 8 I/O pins, two 3.3V, and two GND connections on a two row 2.54mm header. I have a few kicking around from a more complex ones, down to a simple 8 DIP switch and a 7 segment display.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
