<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>BVCC on James Horton</title>
        <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/tags/bvcc/</link>
        <description>Recent content in BVCC on James Horton</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jjhorton.co.uk/tags/bvcc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Week Two in Scotland</title>
        <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/week-two-in-scotland/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/week-two-in-scotland/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/544146_10151527924663011_1555724195_n.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Week Two in Scotland" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Well week 2 wasn&amp;rsquo;t much different to week 1, with there still being no water in Scotland. As a result much of the time was spent walking and sight seeing rather than kayaking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/DSCF2758.JPG&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We paddled the River Awe, which allowed us to see some interesting signs, hide Richards boat in the middle of the river and experience a bit of white water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/DSCF2696.JPG&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/DSCF2697.JPG&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily the River Garry was releasing again this week, which gave me opportunity to get my head wet, as well as practice my air brace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/482860_10151593707651079_1922721987_n.jpg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photo by &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/aoifestrahan&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Aoife Strahan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/544146_10151527924663011_1555724195_n.jpg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;
Photo By Phil Porter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from that there was just much driving, walking, sight seeing and general relaxing at the spa - Certainly not the 2 weeks away that I had
planned in my mind but a relaxing holiday instead. Lets just hope for some more water next time!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The final day in the kayak</title>
        <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/the-final-day-in-the-kayak/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/the-final-day-in-the-kayak/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/DSCF1027.JPG" alt="Featured image of post The final day in the kayak" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Well we all knew this days was coming, the final day of kayaking in
Scotland. Having know this was coming we had planned an epic day of
kayaking, all starting with the earliest alarm of the week at 7am, ready
to hit the road at 8am with the satnav&amp;rsquo;s aimed at Glen Etive&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason for this early start would all soon before clear, that being
the longest and hardest walk in that I have ever undertaken, which make
the walk in on the Garry seem small in comparison. This river is a
tributary to the River Etive, the Allt a&amp;rsquo; Chaorainn, This river as
described by richard &amp;ldquo;is gravity feed, water is only required for
lubrication&amp;rdquo;, and I can&amp;rsquo;t say he isn&amp;rsquo;t wrong. With the early start and
the long hike, when we were stood in the middle of nowhere at 10am,
ready to hit the water I was hoping he was right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/DSCF0989.JPG&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the 5 off use who took our boats along for the long hike the effort
easily justified, taking us down huge rock slides, narrow slots while
testing our ability to dodge rocks. As we went down the river we
were accompanied by Rhiannon, Ian and Emma who had been entrusted  with
the cameras, so hopefully the photos should appear over the next few
days of the trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/ScotlandSlide2012.jpg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Me making my way down Pinball Machine&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After arriving at the bottom of the river we packed the boats into the
back of richards Van, and prepared to head off to do what everyone had
been waiting for, the Etive. For many people including myself this was
the opportunity to run some of the biggest drops we have ever done, as
well as get some new Facebook profile pictures. We started of at tripple
falls  (which was much more impressive than the other tripple falls I
had done on the Dart Loop!), watching richard to a run first to give use
who had never done it before an idea off the line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/DSCF0998.JPG&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then set up safety, and the first guys and girls where off with
Rhiannon following Richard down, she made it successfully down the first
drop, only to go over at the bottom. Following a failed attempt at
rolling, then taking a swim beween the first and second drop. She was
then followed by Polina, who powered down both the first and second
drop successfully and even survived a few iffy moments in the eddy
bellow the drop. Bob, followed the girls down, making a point of saying
hello to Mike on the way down although we don&amp;rsquo;t think it was
intentional! With the 4 off them back in the boats they made there way
down the final drop with Polina taking a swim at the bottom. Myself and
Zoe, then joined richard to a quick run from top to bottom, with
Richards only run to be caught on camera he messed up. Not to mention
Zoe needing Richards Help after ending up against the wall at the bottom
of the 3rd drop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/DSCF1027.JPG&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the bottom, most people pilled into the cars and headed off to right
angle falls, with Richard, Zoe, Bob and myself paddling down the river
to meet them, while Mike headed down with his camera kit to capture the
action as we paddled down. With both me and Bob having never paddled the
river we were relying on Richard&amp;rsquo;s and Zoe&amp;rsquo;s memory, Richard took the
lead, for another amazing section of river. With each feature known not
my its name but by who ran it, and who/what got broken there when the
university group paddled it last year. The quick pace off the run made
it really enjoyable, with quick inspections off the features, and the
small number of us allowing for a quick run of the river. The run was
uneventful, apart from Zoe&amp;rsquo;s swim at letter box, for which richard wins
the award of most useless throw line for (all will be explained when the
video appears).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were soon down at Right Angle Falls, and ready to do the biggest
waterfall that many off us had ever done. The girls who had done tripple
falls  took the option for Richard to launch them from directly above
the drop, both completing it successfully, albeit with a bit of swimming
after. The time came for my run, and I seemed to go for the option off
keep paddling and then air brace (something I seem to have a habit
of), disappearing underwater for sometime, but resurfacing upright,
meaning I managed to stay upright for the whole trip, without the need
for a single roll!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/RightAngle2012.jpg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Me heading over right angle falls&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the time we were are Right Angle Falls every single weather
Scotland could trow at us had come though; Sun, Rain, Wind, Hail and
Snow, but Nothing seemed to be able to wipe the smile of peoples faces,
it was a great way to end the weeks paddling, now time to pack up ready
for most people to hit the road home tomorrow, while I&amp;rsquo;ll be off
Mountain Biking.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>First day in Scotland</title>
        <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/first-day-in-scotland/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/first-day-in-scotland/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/FirstDayScotland.jpg" alt="Featured image of post First day in Scotland" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the long drive yesterday, today we hit the first river off the
trip the River Loche. Although you would think the rivers would have had
enough of driving following the 100&amp;rsquo;s of miles covered yesterday,
everyone seemed to enough the rally stage like road which takes you to
the get on, the single track making a nice change to the motorway and A
roads everyone had been traveling on yesterday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/DSCF0816.JPG&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This river was a gentle start to the trip, with the river being mostly
flat. It was also our first opportunity to paddle as a group, and see
how everyones paddling was, as well as get comfortable in our boats. The
river has only one small feature, but more than enough to keep everyone
entertains in the small feature that is half way down the river.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
