<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>BVCC on James Horton</title>
    <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/tags/bvcc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in BVCC on James Horton</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jjhorton.co.uk/tags/bvcc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Last minute trip to Dartmoor</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/last-minute-trip-to-dartmoor/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/last-minute-trip-to-dartmoor/</guid>
      <description>The original plan for the weekend was for a BVCC club trip up to Yorkshire to sample some of the white water that is on offer up North, but it wasn’t too be. Not to be put of by the lack of water up north arrangements were for a few of us to head south instead, and down to Dartmoor. With the rooms booked in a local Travelodge on the Thursday night, and rain forecast it was looking like a good shout.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week Two in Scotland</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/week-two-in-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/week-two-in-scotland/</guid>
      <description>Well week 2 wasn&amp;rsquo;t much different to week 1, with there still being no water in Scotland. As a result much of the time was spent walking and sight seeing rather than kayaking.
 
We paddled the River Awe, which allowed us to see some interesting signs, hide Richards boat in the middle of the river and experience a bit of white water.
 
 
Luckily the River Garry was releasing again this week, which gave me opportunity to get my head wet, as well as practice my air brace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The final day in the kayak</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/the-final-day-in-the-kayak/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/the-final-day-in-the-kayak/</guid>
      <description>Well we all knew this days was coming, the final day of kayaking in Scotland. Having know this was coming we had planned an epic day of kayaking, all starting with the earliest alarm of the week at 7am, ready to hit the road at 8am with the satnav&amp;rsquo;s aimed at Glen Etive
The reason for this early start would all soon before clear, that being the longest and hardest walk in that I have ever undertaken, which make the walk in on the Garry seem small in comparison.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First day in Scotland</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/first-day-in-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/first-day-in-scotland/</guid>
      <description>After the long drive yesterday, today we hit the first river off the trip the River Loche. Although you would think the rivers would have had enough of driving following the 100&amp;rsquo;s of miles covered yesterday, everyone seemed to enough the rally stage like road which takes you to the get on, the single track making a nice change to the motorway and A roads everyone had been traveling on yesterday.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
