<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Surfing on James Horton</title>
        <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/tags/surfing/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Surfing on James Horton</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-uk</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jjhorton.co.uk/tags/surfing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Falls of Lora</title>
        <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/falls-of-lora/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/falls-of-lora/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/FallsofLora.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Falls of Lora" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today we were up early, for the second day of paddling we were going to do something a bit stupid, the falls of lora.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Fall of Lora are formed as the tide changes, and lasts for a few hours, with the height of the tide determining how and which waves form. Today happened to be one off the biggest of the year and we happened to be there, an opportunity to be missed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Me and Richard were the only ones stupid/brave enough to give it a go, joining the large numbers of locals, and university groups that had turned out to see what it is all about. Getting there nice and early to watch it form we then hoped of the water at around 11:30, with the
wave still building. Richard was at home on the wave enjoying a good surf and play of the wave, unlike me. I was struggling with the huge eddie line and still not feeling at home in my playboat, as a result I only had a few goes which I didn&amp;rsquo;t achieve much in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we were here the rest of the group went on to paddle the River Awe, but we decided rather than chasing them the local cafe along with an hour in the spa was a better idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/IMG_8556.JPG&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
