<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>pelican on James Horton</title>
        <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/tags/pelican/</link>
        <description>Recent content in pelican on James Horton</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jjhorton.co.uk/tags/pelican/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>New Website</title>
        <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/new_website/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/new_website/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/pelican_website.png" alt="Featured image of post New Website" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Well I have finally got around to starting to sort my website out, after my old
one disappeared from the internet. It seems that no one really noticed it was missing
from the internet, so I must have just been talking to myself!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The old site was a Wordpress blog that I had been using on and off since 2011,
I&amp;rsquo;d also had various attempts at a website since  getting my own domain 2006.
The Wordpress had done well but I hadn&amp;rsquo;t updated in over a year when I got rid
of it, unable to justify paying for hosting a blog that I have never really had
time to update regularly since I finished university.There was a reasonable
amount of content on the site, but a lot of the original posts didn&amp;rsquo;t really
work as Wordpress had lost some of the features I used and a number of key
plug-in I used were no longer available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this is the new site&amp;hellip; Or it will be once I have finished making it work, the
replacement website is now hosted using &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://pages.github.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Github Pages&lt;/a&gt;,
and is a statically generated HTML site created using
&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://docs.getpelican.com/en/stable/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt;. Hopefully it will
be easy to keep working and slightly more up-to date than my old blog was!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
