<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>USCC on James Horton</title>
        <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/tags/uscc/</link>
        <description>Recent content in USCC on James Horton</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jjhorton.co.uk/tags/uscc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Week one in Scotland</title>
        <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/week-one-in-scotland/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/week-one-in-scotland/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/DSCF2219.JPG" alt="Featured image of post Week one in Scotland" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This last week I have been in the Fort William area with the university
of Surrey Canoe Club, for a week of white water paddling. Despite Fort
William being known for giving reliable white water we managed to pick
the time of year were there was no rain, and only snow!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/IMG_0363.JPG&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The journey up to Fort William had been a battle, with the country being
hit by large snowfall and high wind warning along almost the entire
route, but all the vehicles managed to make it along the A82 without
incident, unlike many cars that were seen along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/DSCF2633.JPG&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We stayed near the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.inchree.co.uk/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Inchree Chalets&lt;/a&gt;, not far
outside fort william, with 3 of them rented for the group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sunday&#34;&gt;Sunday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/DSCF2219.JPG&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite being warned of the low water, we were hopeful that at least
some of the rivers would run, but it was today that we realized just how
little water was going to be about, unless we got some more rain. The
first river we tried was the Spean Gorge Section, which should be
runnable in most levels, but as we soon found out most levels doesn’t
include as low as this. Many sections that we would have expected to
find features were none existent, and some not even passable, with the
portage becoming a way of life. This is also before you coincided the
long flat water scrape back to the vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;monday&#34;&gt;Monday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/DSCF2238.JPG&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the lack of water the day before, instead of heading of kayaking
most of the group went for a walk to look at the Inchree Falls that were
located close to the bunkhouse. With much of the group going for an
explore around the falls which have been run a handful of times,
followed by a number of people scaling a nearby hill, to see the view,
and the snow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tuesday&#34;&gt;Tuesday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/DSCF2287.JPG&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the group not managing to get on the water the day before, we
decided to give the Arkaig a go, this river runs between 2 lochs, but
even this does not guarantee there will be any water. The river was
found to be runnable, if not completely different to how it would be
normally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/DSCF2300.JPG&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the group ran the main rapid multiple times, making use of the
water and the short walk back up. At the get off to the river is a
bridge going over the loch, which many people may have jumped off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/DSCF2375.JPG&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;wednesday&#34;&gt;Wednesday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not for the first time this week we found the lack of water an issue, so a number of the group decide to go and make use of another form of white water up in Glencoe, and go skiing instead. With the remainder of the
group taking a walk up the River Nevis in the afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;thursday&#34;&gt;Thursday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today we had some guaranteed water in the form of the first dam release
of the year on the River Garry. This made a welcome break from the rest
of the week were the group were able to paddle without scraping along
the rocks like previous rivers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/DSCF2489.JPG&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we arrived at the get on the river was quiet and the water was
still rising, but it didn’t take long for the river level to have risen
and the car park to have been filled. The river had large numbers of
groups, making the most of the release to get out paddling with a number
of university groups around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/DSCF2465.JPG&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following on from a good few runs we heading to the Moriston to see what
the levels looked like up there, but the lack of water was easy to see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;friday&#34;&gt;Friday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/DSCF2525.JPG&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the first day of the week the river level in the Etive had picked up enough to make it worth a fun, so the group decided to jump on for a run while they could. Triple Falls had enough water to fall over, along with a scrap through bits in between that the group was able to run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/DSCF2620.JPG&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All this was enough to ensure that people got some photos of them
falling over right angle falls before the final day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now the university group head backs to Guildford, but i’ve got another
week of waiting for the rain gods to provide some water&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
