<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ECP5 on James Horton</title>
    <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/tags/ecp5/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ECP5 on James Horton</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jjhorton.co.uk/tags/ecp5/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with Ice Sugar Pro </title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/icesugarpro/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/icesugarpro/</guid>
      <description>Having previously purchased a several FPGA development boards, this is the latest one for working with both Yosys and Next-pnr, an open source FPGA tool chain. I have brought 2 of these other boards which are both based around the color light modules, these boards are avalible as both the Lattice ECP5 FPGA Colorlight i5 Development Board and Lattice ECP5 FPGA Colorlight i9 Development Board. They include a breakout board that allows you to connect PMod Modules, HDMI (Which i&amp;rsquo;ve never used) and a USB-C port that allows the connection of a computer to do the programming and serial connections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Opensource FPGA tools for ECP5 Evaluation Board</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/ecp5g-eval/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/ecp5g-eval/</guid>
      <description>In this post I am recording how I got my first design onto the ECP5 Development board that I recently purchased. This devboard makes use of the LFE5UM5G FPGA, on a pcb, with lots of IO broken out including the SERDES Pins. For this example, I am using the on-board 8 LED&amp;rsquo;s, and an example that I originally used with my icebreaker board and an LED PMod.
Getting the ECP5 Devboard setup As a Macbook Air user, with its M1 processor, sometimes means getting the right tools can be a challenge.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
