<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on James Horton</title>
    <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on James Horton</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading the christmas countdown with GPS</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/chrismas_gps_countdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/chrismas_gps_countdown/</guid>
      <description>The countdown timer that I created last year, which used my custom RP2040 Pmod board with the PMod Severn Segment Display I had also created, was in need of an upgrade. The main aim of this project was to replace the Raspberry Pi Zero that provided the time data to what was just a display made of my custom hardware, and turn it into something that can run automonously, by getting that time data from a GPS reveiver.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a GPS PMod Board</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/gps_pmod_board/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/gps_pmod_board/</guid>
      <description>I have been looking to put together a GPS board for a while, as I had a few ideas for upgrading a project with realtime time information, and a few things that I could try out if I had location or time data, as well as an accurate timing pulse source. While there are actually plenty of options for just buying a pre-made PMod module, I decided I would be better of giving it a go myself as I wanted a few of them and that could make it cheaper to build my own if I needed a few.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started IKEA Vindriktning in Home Assistant with Pico W</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/ikea-air_quality-sensor/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/ikea-air_quality-sensor/</guid>
      <description>The IKEA Vindriktning is an air quality sensor sold for just £13, that makes use of a PM1006 sensor inside to detect particle matter in the air. Normally the readins from the sensor are displayed on one of 3 LED&amp;rsquo;s on the front of the unit, but here we are looking to collect this data and add it into Home Assistant .
There are a large number of posts and instructions avalible online for modifying the IKEA Vindriktning or removing the PM1006 sensor and building a Home Assistant integrated sensor using an ECP32 module.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with Ice Sugar Pro </title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/icesugarpro/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/icesugarpro/</guid>
      <description>Having previously purchased a several FPGA development boards, this is the latest one for working with both Yosys and Next-pnr, an open source FPGA tool chain. I have brought 2 of these other boards which are both based around the color light modules, these boards are avalible as both the Lattice ECP5 FPGA Colorlight i5 Development Board and Lattice ECP5 FPGA Colorlight i9 Development Board. They include a breakout board that allows you to connect PMod Modules, HDMI (Which i&amp;rsquo;ve never used) and a USB-C port that allows the connection of a computer to do the programming and serial connections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Controlling Neopixels with iceBreaker FPGA </title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/neopixelfirmware/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/neopixelfirmware/</guid>
      <description>Having perviously got my Neopixel PCB working with my RP2040 Board, i&amp;rsquo;ve be wanting to spend some time building up a FPGA example, that has some of the same functionality. For this I wanted to build an example in Verilog that could be deployed to my icebreaker FPGA devboard, with its ice40 FPGA which as 5K LUTs is a great match for this task with it serial over USB link and PMod Connectors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Opensource FPGA tools for ECP5 Evaluation Board</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/ecp5g-eval/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/ecp5g-eval/</guid>
      <description>In this post I am recording how I got my first design onto the ECP5 Development board that I recently purchased. This devboard makes use of the LFE5UM5G FPGA, on a pcb, with lots of IO broken out including the SERDES Pins. For this example, I am using the on-board 8 LED&amp;rsquo;s, and an example that I originally used with my icebreaker board and an LED PMod.
Getting the ECP5 Devboard setup As a Macbook Air user, with its M1 processor, sometimes means getting the right tools can be a challenge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding FPGA build stats to Github Pull requests</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/fpga-build-stats/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/fpga-build-stats/</guid>
      <description>The pervious post on building the LED example is Firmware Testing and aims to add the building of the FPGA for the iceBreaker FPGA board. The FPGA image will be built using the github actions workflow that is similar to that which was used in my post but with the addition of adding some detailed comments in the pull requests and using the Lattice ice40 part in place of the Lattice ECP5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Continuous Integration for Firmware testing using Verilator</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/firmware-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/firmware-testing/</guid>
      <description>I was looking to build a simple flashing LED example using my IceBreaker FPGA Board, for this I wanted to build on CI tools I set up before, and add some more useful testing to my setup. First of all lets look at what we are aiming to build, the PMOD board has 8 LED&amp;rsquo;s each connected to a single pin, setting the IO pin high turns the LED on. With one LED on at a time, cycling though all the LED&amp;rsquo;s one at a time at a speed which is easily slow enough to see.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Website Upgrade</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/website-upgrade/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/website-upgrade/</guid>
      <description>Every 5 years I seem to upgrade my website, in 2012 I upgraded my old static site to a wordpress site, then 5 years later in 2017 I changed to a static HTML website generated by Pelican. This statically generated website was hosted on github pages, this is a setup I liked, with all my website files stored in git and then deployed automatically with github workflows when I merged a pull request with a new post in it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neopixel Drinks Coaster</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/rp2040_coaster/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/rp2040_coaster/</guid>
      <description>This little project involved building something unnecessarily complex when there are many much cheaper options that would have done the job just fine. The reason for this was that my girlfriend likes the light up gin bottles from Marks and Spencer&amp;rsquo;s, and I though there could be a better way to create my own, and if your going to have a Light up bottle, it is always going to be improved by having programable RGB LED&amp;rsquo;s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christmas Countdown</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/christmascountdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/christmascountdown/</guid>
      <description>Christmas Countdown on the Whiteboard Using my 7 segment display I wanted to build a Christmas countdown, this was just going to use the PMod Display that I had around, and then run from one of the RP2040 boards that I built earlier this year. As I wanted a count down that is frequently updating, I chose to use the countdown in seconds, as this for the month of December easily fits within the seven segments available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing PCB Filters using MATLAB</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/matlabpcbfilters/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/matlabpcbfilters/</guid>
      <description>Mathworks released the RF PCB Toolbox with the latest release of MATLAB, R2021B, this toolbox allows the creation and visualisation of &amp;ldquo;Transmission lines, Couplers, Splitters, Filters, and More&amp;rdquo;, this was something that I wanted to a go at particularly the design of the filters. These filters that are just made of PCB traces have always fascinated me and given the tools that should allow me to design them, I decided to give it a go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seven Segment Display PMod Board</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/sevensegmentdisp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/sevensegmentdisp/</guid>
      <description>Ive always wanted to build a severn segment display, there is something about the old school style displays that it is hard to beat to display random numerical data like in the movies.
The 7 Segment display that I decided to use, comes with 4 digits per display, and I was looking to combine two per PMod Board, with 8 LED per segment, we don&amp;rsquo;t have enough pins to be able to control them all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infrared Sensors and Neopixel screen</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/infraredsensorneopixel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/infraredsensorneopixel/</guid>
      <description>After perviously building a PMod Infrared Sensor board, that was perviously streaming data over the serial link from the RP2040 PMod board to a PC which was using Python to display the data. The next step is to look at using a screen to display the data from the infrared Sensor.
The screen that I looked to use is a custom board based on using the Neopixel LED&amp;rsquo;s that I have previously used with the RP2040 board, this allows a simple way to display the data, the screen which is also a 8x8 grid the same resolution as the sensor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RP2040 PMod PCB</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/rp2040_pmod/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/rp2040_pmod/</guid>
      <description>Having perviously built myself a Pico PMod Board around the Raspberry Pi Pico, I wanted to take this to the next level, and build myself a few boards from scratch. So once the orders went live for the RP2040 microcontroller a few months ago, I ordered some, and then did nothing with them for a while.
Like many people, I seem to end up with more ideas than time and it took me a little while to get around to this one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PMod 8x8 Infrared Sensor</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/infraredsensorpmod/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/infraredsensorpmod/</guid>
      <description>Building a PMod Based board with an 8x8 Infrared Sensor</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inspectrum with SigMF Files</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/inspectrumsigmf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/inspectrumsigmf/</guid>
      <description>This post is as much a note to myself, for the next time that I hit this issue, which is installing Inspectrum with SigMF support.
The tool I&amp;rsquo;m installing is Inspectrum which is for analysing captured files of sampled data, primarily from Software Defined Radios. This allows for looking at signals, and analysing what is in the capture. I was looking to use this tool with some SigMF files, the Signal Meta data files are made up of a Binary File containing the sample data, and a JSON companion file, which contains details about the capture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pico PMod breakout PCB</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/picopmod/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/picopmod/</guid>
      <description>Pico on a Breadboard After picking up a few Raspberry Pi Pico&amp;rsquo;s, I was looking for a use for them and I decided to hook up a few of the PMod boards I have from playing around with FPGA. This PMod boards all use the same pinout, of 12 pins, which consists of 8 I/O pins, two 3.3V, and two GND connections on a two row 2.54mm header. I have a few kicking around from a more complex ones, down to a simple 8 DIP switch and a 7 segment display.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Filter Testing</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/filtertesting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/filtertesting/</guid>
      <description>This post is going to take a look at some Filters that I have &amp;ldquo;made at home&amp;rdquo;, for when I am experimenting with my Software Defined Radio&amp;rsquo;s. The filters are for use in the 433MHz band, and I wanted to create some bandpass filters to improve the IQ Recordings I was making, as I was getting a lot of out of band interference on my Pluto SDR.
For a 433MHz Filter I could have just purchased some pre-made boards, complete with some simple filters on ebay, there were plenty of options but they all seemed a little expensive, so what harm is there in just having a look at trying to build something myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Continuous Integration for Firmware with Github Actions</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/firmwareci/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/firmwareci/</guid>
      <description>For a couple of months I&amp;rsquo;ve been slowly building up a little project using some Development boards that include an FPGA, typically once i&amp;rsquo;ve finished editing my design I run all my simulations, tests and then check I can still build the firmware. While running these manually before each commit isn&amp;rsquo;t typically much an issue, I wanted to automate this.
The project i&amp;rsquo;m working on uses a ColorLite i5 FPGA board, this with it Lattice ECP5 FPGA allows me to use a set of Open source tools to test and build my FPGA images.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nvidia Jetson Nano 2Gb Testing</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/jetsontesting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/jetsontesting/</guid>
      <description>Now that I have the Jetson Nano all setup in a case, I wanted to test out a how well the GPU works on some simple problems. This post looks at my first test which looks at a simple method of calculating Pi, and looks at how quickly is can carry out those calculations.
This method of calculating Pi is oftern refered to as the dart board method. This method relies on placing random number onto a square and then determining if that random number falls within a circle with a diameter that is the same size as the box or in the area outside of the circle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nvidia Jetson case</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/jetson2gbcase/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/jetson2gbcase/</guid>
      <description>Before Christmas I picked up a 2GB Jetson Nano to have a play with, I think these devices are interesting with the combination of an ARM processor and GPU. There have been devices like this before, and we even have a spare one at work in our Makerspace but I never found time to have an experiment with one. Now with extra time on my hands over winter with the joy of home working, and the recently released 2GB version for about £55 meant it was time to have an experiment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bring a Raspberry Pi Cluster Back to Life</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/piclusterreborn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/piclusterreborn/</guid>
      <description>The raspberry pi cluster was built several years ago for some projects I was doing at the time, and experimenting with parallel computing. While the little raspberry pi&amp;rsquo;s were never going to keep up with a proper PC, they were great for experimenting with the principles of parallel computing, being it making use of the multiple CPU cores on each device or trying to spread the calculation over multiple raspberry pi&amp;rsquo;s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Website</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/new_website/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/new_website/</guid>
      <description>Final starting to get my website up and running again, now hosted on github pages and using pelican</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World back online</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/first_post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/first_post/</guid>
      <description>Is anyone there? Trying to get my wedbsite working Again&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Octave on my Raspberry Pi Cluster</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/octave-on-my-raspberry-pi-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/octave-on-my-raspberry-pi-cluster/</guid>
      <description>The main aim of building my Raspberry Pi Cluster was so that I could run octave code on it, now I&amp;rsquo;m not expecting to break any records, but ideally I want some performance. The best way I found to do this was with the parallel&amp;rsquo;s package.
With octave and the parallels package installed on each of the Raspberry Pi 2&amp;rsquo;s in the cluster, I setup SSH so that no passwords are required between the nodes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Over clocking my Raspberry Pi cluster</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/over-clocking-my-raspberry-pi-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/over-clocking-my-raspberry-pi-cluster/</guid>
      <description>With my newly created raspberry pi cluster being made out of the Raspberry Pi 2, I don&amp;rsquo;t want it to lag to far behind the freshly announced Raspberry Pi 3. To try and keep up with the new hardware without replacing all of my Pi&amp;rsquo;s I devices it was worth a go at overclocking them.
Overlooking my Pi&amp;rsquo;s should allow them to work a bit quicker, but it will reduce power efficient and increase the tempurature that the cluster runs at.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Raspberry Pi Cluster</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/building-a-raspberry-pi-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/building-a-raspberry-pi-cluster/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had a long standing interest in Parallel Processing, and then a few months ago I came across Octave and its parallel package. Octave is very similar to MATLAB that I use every day, and for the most part basic MATLAB code works out of the box in Octave.
I used this as the perfect excuse to build myself a mini-cluster computer&amp;hellip;
The mini cluster needed to be cheep, so I based it on the raspberry pi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last minute trip to Dartmoor</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/last-minute-trip-to-dartmoor/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/last-minute-trip-to-dartmoor/</guid>
      <description>The original plan for the weekend was for a BVCC club trip up to Yorkshire to sample some of the white water that is on offer up North, but it wasn’t too be. Not to be put of by the lack of water up north arrangements were for a few of us to head south instead, and down to Dartmoor. With the rooms booked in a local Travelodge on the Thursday night, and rain forecast it was looking like a good shout.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Popping into Wales for a paddle</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/popping-into-wales-for-a-paddle/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/popping-into-wales-for-a-paddle/</guid>
      <description>With most of the country suffering with storms and rain over the Christmas period one of the few groups of people who were looking out the window all excited were the kayakers…
I think the ford maybe a bit to deep today, time to find another way around #flood pic.twitter.com/FylGGkijTS
&amp;mdash; James Horton (@JamesjHorton) January 2, 2014 Unfortunately unable to get out paddling until after the new year we hit the road on the Friday after new year to meet up in Swansea ready for a bit of paddling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A weekend on the Wye</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/a-weekend-on-the-wye/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/a-weekend-on-the-wye/</guid>
      <description>After reaching the end of yet another year at uni (and almost the end of my time there), I tagged along with Blackwater Valley Canoe Club (BVCC) for a trip along the River Wye.
As I no longer have much to do with my time (expect move out my old house), I decided to take an extra day off, and head across to the Black Mountains for a bonus day of cycling in the unusually sunny Wales.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>36 Hours in North Wales</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/36-hours-in-north-wales/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/36-hours-in-north-wales/</guid>
      <description>After the lack of paddling while up in scotland the opportunity came for to spend the weekend up in north wales with Bromley Canoe Club. Unfortunately yet again it was looking like there would still be a complete lack of water, but knowing that at least the River Dee would be running I packed my Playboat and in the early hours of Saturday Morning headed to the bunkhouse they were staying at.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week Two in Scotland</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/week-two-in-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/week-two-in-scotland/</guid>
      <description>Well week 2 wasn&amp;rsquo;t much different to week 1, with there still being no water in Scotland. As a result much of the time was spent walking and sight seeing rather than kayaking.
We paddled the River Awe, which allowed us to see some interesting signs, hide Richards boat in the middle of the river and experience a bit of white water.
Luckily the River Garry was releasing again this week, which gave me opportunity to get my head wet, as well as practice my air brace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week one in Scotland</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/week-one-in-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/week-one-in-scotland/</guid>
      <description>This last week I have been in the Fort William area with the university of Surrey Canoe Club, for a week of white water paddling. Despite Fort William being known for giving reliable white water we managed to pick the time of year were there was no rain, and only snow!
The journey up to Fort William had been a battle, with the country being hit by large snowfall and high wind warning along almost the entire route, but all the vehicles managed to make it along the A82 without incident, unlike many cars that were seen along the way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lake District</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/lake-district/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/lake-district/</guid>
      <description>Last weekend I joined Blackwater Valley Canoe Club for a trip unto the Lake District, for most of the people going they were heading up on Thursday making the most of the February half term. Unfortunately we don’t get half terms at university, so I had to wait until my final lecture had finished at 5pm on Friday to hit the road and head north, which as it turns out is a very long way!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping in Matlab</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/mapping-in-matlab/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/mapping-in-matlab/</guid>
      <description>As part of a project that I&amp;rsquo;m completing in my masters course at university I found that I need to plot data on a map, specifically the routes of undersea cables that pass though the oceans and the depth of the sea bed. My group needed this information so that we would be able to prove that the plan we had for the product we were producing had a suitable depth rating as well as being in range of the cables we were going to be fixing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A cold weekend in Dartmoor</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/a-cold-weekend-in-dartmoor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/a-cold-weekend-in-dartmoor/</guid>
      <description>Last weekend was spent in one of the places that I have kayaked the most, dartmoor. Although trips here normally revole around the river dart, normally on the loop and upper this time we found ourselves looking further afield. Paddling with 4 friends from uni on the same weekend that the River Source event the aim was to try and avoid the country park as best we could.
Our accommodation for the weekend was a YHA camping barn which is basic at best, very different to the usual bunkhouses with beds and central heating.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A weekend on the Barle</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/a-weekend-on-the-barle/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/a-weekend-on-the-barle/</guid>
      <description>For the 4th year in a row a trip down the River Barle marks the start of my winter white water session here in the Uk. The river Barle being my second white water kayaking trip seems like a long time ago, paddling for survival in one of the University of Surrey Canoe Club boats on my second trip since starting university. Now 4 years on I find myself drifting down the river in my play boat drifting along enjoying the sights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low Cost Quad Rotor Design and Implementation Report</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/low-cost-quad-rotor-design-and-implementation-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/low-cost-quad-rotor-design-and-implementation-report/</guid>
      <description>Now that the project is long finished and my marks for the year have been given I thought I would share the final report for the project.
Although the project was not completed, with me unable to finish tuning the PID control loops to a standard were it would be able to fly, I was successfully able to get the quad rotor to be able to balance most of the time on its test jig.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hurley for the day</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/hurley-for-the-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/hurley-for-the-day/</guid>
      <description>After nearly 4 years of paddling I&amp;rsquo;ve finally got around to getting some qualifications, the first one a few weeks ago was the FSRT (Foundation Safety and Rescue) Training. The training was run by Simon from backwater valley canoe club and was good fun, even though last year I did my advanced white water safety and rescue. We did the course on the river Thames, nearly Hurley weir and to break the day up we couldn&amp;rsquo;t say no to a quick play on the weir which was on 2 gates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serial Communication and MATLAB</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/serial-control-and-matlab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/serial-control-and-matlab/</guid>
      <description>For producing the Quad Rotor&amp;rsquo;s GUI I needed to be able to implement the serial communication in MATLAB. This it seemed would be a simple task as on windows machines it is a simple task of opening the comms port, send the data, and closing the port. All seemed so simple, but as it turns out this was not the case on the Mac which I was using from my project with MATLAB R2008a</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The journey home begins</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/the-journey-home-begins/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/the-journey-home-begins/</guid>
      <description>With everyone up and awake early, they knew they had a long journey ahead, with the chalets clean everyone hit the road for home, well not quiet everyone. I headed in the opposite direction, with my sights set of the Nevis Range. This was another chance to have a run at some of the routes I had done on Wednesday. This time I only managed to do the Championship Red Route, having not fully recovered from yesterdays kayaking, with it taking me longer this time than it did on Wednesday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The final day in the kayak</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/the-final-day-in-the-kayak/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/the-final-day-in-the-kayak/</guid>
      <description>Well we all knew this days was coming, the final day of kayaking in Scotland. Having know this was coming we had planned an epic day of kayaking, all starting with the earliest alarm of the week at 7am, ready to hit the road at 8am with the satnav&amp;rsquo;s aimed at Glen Etive
The reason for this early start would all soon before clear, that being the longest and hardest walk in that I have ever undertaken, which make the walk in on the Garry seem small in comparison.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Communication Control</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/communication-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/communication-control/</guid>
      <description>For the Quad rotor to work I need some control over it, I have got my communications link all set up, but I need to sort out what I&amp;rsquo;m going to send over it. Previously I had just been sending gyroscope or accelerometer readings, but now this needs to become a two way system and for that I need to write some code at both ends that is up to the task.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Falls of Lora</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/falls-of-lora/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/falls-of-lora/</guid>
      <description>Today we were up early, for the second day of paddling we were going to do something a bit stupid, the falls of lora.
The Fall of Lora are formed as the tide changes, and lasts for a few hours, with the height of the tide determining how and which waves form. Today happened to be one off the biggest of the year and we happened to be there, an opportunity to be missed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First day in Scotland</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/first-day-in-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/first-day-in-scotland/</guid>
      <description>After the long drive yesterday, today we hit the first river off the trip the River Loche. Although you would think the rivers would have had enough of driving following the 100&amp;rsquo;s of miles covered yesterday, everyone seemed to enough the rally stage like road which takes you to the get on, the single track making a nice change to the motorway and A roads everyone had been traveling on yesterday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting the Rotors Running</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/getting-the-rotors-running/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/getting-the-rotors-running/</guid>
      <description>After several weeks off nothing happening, then hitting problems with the filtering i&amp;rsquo;ve finally found sometime to get some work done on my project. This week I have been getting the rotors running, which is surprisingly simple no that I know how it all works.
With my project being based on an Arduino Nano processor I was able to use the Servo Library, although this is mainly aimed at controlling servo&amp;rsquo;s it also works for ESC&amp;rsquo;s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Packed and ready to hit the road to Scotland</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/packed-and-ready-to-hit-the-road-to-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/packed-and-ready-to-hit-the-road-to-scotland/</guid>
      <description>Well the time has come for my first trip to scotland, and its been a long time coming. Most people who take up kayaking tend to end up kayaking as many places at home before the head overseas, but for me the sunshine in the alps has ment I&amp;rsquo;ve never headed north beyond Yorkshire.
So what to take to scotland? Well the big boats in, thats a given but I&amp;rsquo;m also taking the Playboat, I don&amp;rsquo;t know why at the moment but I&amp;rsquo;m sure that it&amp;rsquo;ll hit the water at some point over the 10 days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Communication</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/communication/</guid>
      <description>For the communication system, there are many choices available from the traditional route of model building and control. The main issue with these systems is that they are very expensive, so for my project I have chosen to use a Bluetooth module.
The module that I have chosen is the Spark fun Bluetooth Mate Silver from proto-pic.co.uk, this simply attaches to the RX and TX lines on the arduino processor that I’m using, this makes the communication very simple, helping to reduce the development time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Processing Power</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/processing-power/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/processing-power/</guid>
      <description>To get everything talking together I’m going to need something to sit in the middle, and provide all the processing power. On the recommendation of my supervisor I had a look at the arduino boards. The arduino boards are based on Atmel processors in the middle with a boot loader per-installed to allow the uploading of programs straight onto the board from USB.
Arduino Nano Board There are many variants of the processor available, all with more than enough programming power for what I will be doing, the important thing for me to consider was which input and output interfaces I’d need for my quad rotor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quad Rotor Project, Introduction</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/quad-rotor-project-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/quad-rotor-project-introduction/</guid>
      <description>Well one day after looking though pictures of these magical 4 rotor helicopter type things hovering, I was sold it was a good idea… that was over a year ago, and now I’m building one for my 3^rd^ year project at university. The quad rotor uses 4 rotors, 2 rotating one way and 2 going the in the opposite direction. The forces can be shown on a simple wire frame model</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello world!</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>Well this is it, I finally gave up writing my own blog and just installed one.
Now I just need to find some content to fill it with!
Updated: This was for my old wordpress based website, since been upgraded</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
