<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Bluetooth on James Horton</title>
        <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/tags/bluetooth/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Bluetooth on James Horton</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-uk</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jjhorton.co.uk/tags/bluetooth/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Communication</title>
        <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/communication/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/communication/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/BluetoothPcb.png" alt="Featured image of post Communication" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the communication system, there are many choices available from the
traditional route of model building and control. The main issue with
these systems is that they are very expensive, so for my project I have
chosen to use a Bluetooth module.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/BluetoothPcb.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The module that I have chosen is the Spark fun Bluetooth Mate Silver
from &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://proto-pic.co.uk&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;proto-pic.co.uk&lt;/a&gt;, this simply attaches to
the RX and TX lines on the arduino processor that I’m using, this makes
the communication very simple, helping to reduce the development time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jjhorton.co.uk/img/BluetoothHelloWorld.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bluetooth module is mounted on the same main board as my processor,
and only required a few quick solder connections to start getting some
response on my computer. To start with a found that I wasn’t getting
anything that I expected out of the board, but looking though the
datasheets as well as a few useful posts on the
&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://sparkfun.com&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;sparkfun.com&lt;/a&gt; website, I found that the default
baud rate for the Bluetooth module was 115200 not 9600, I had been
trying to use. This quick fix meant that in no time at all I was able to
send data to my computer, and also with a little bit of code be able to
flash an LED.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now to stop turning on and off LED’s and turn this into a quad rotor.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
