<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Continuous Integration on James Horton</title>
    <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/tags/continuous-integration/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Continuous Integration on James Horton</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jjhorton.co.uk/tags/continuous-integration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Continuous Integration for Firmware testing using Verilator</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/firmware-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/firmware-testing/</guid>
      <description>I was looking to build a simple flashing LED example using my IceBreaker FPGA Board, for this I wanted to build on CI tools I set up before, and add some more useful testing to my setup. First of all lets look at what we are aiming to build, the PMOD board has 8 LED&amp;rsquo;s each connected to a single pin, setting the IO pin high turns the LED on. With one LED on at a time, cycling though all the LED&amp;rsquo;s one at a time at a speed which is easily slow enough to see.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Continuous Integration for Firmware with Github Actions</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/firmwareci/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/firmwareci/</guid>
      <description>For a couple of months I&amp;rsquo;ve been slowly building up a little project using some Development boards that include an FPGA, typically once i&amp;rsquo;ve finished editing my design I run all my simulations, tests and then check I can still build the firmware. While running these manually before each commit isn&amp;rsquo;t typically much an issue, I wanted to automate this.
The project i&amp;rsquo;m working on uses a ColorLite i5 FPGA board, this with it Lattice ECP5 FPGA allows me to use a set of Open source tools to test and build my FPGA images.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
