<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>RP2040 on James Horton</title>
    <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/tags/rp2040/</link>
    <description>Recent content in RP2040 on James Horton</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jjhorton.co.uk/tags/rp2040/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>RP2040 Mini PMod</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/rp2040_mini_pmod/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/rp2040_mini_pmod/</guid>
      <description>My pervious RP2040 PMod board included 3 PMod Connectors and a USB-C, this has been a great little board for development and testing but there are a couple of issues with this board. The first problem is the size, I would prefer something a bit smaller, with only a single PMod connector. The second is the lack of some additional storage, for logging data to such as GPS positions, and then finally is the cost with the expensive USB-C connector used on my original design being a particular problem, costing more than the RP2040 Micro Controller.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatically panellization of Kicad PCB&#39;s with github Actions</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/kicad-github-panels/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/kicad-github-panels/</guid>
      <description>As part of my PCB design workflow I use kibot to process my PCB&amp;rsquo;s and generate the Gerber files I need for PCB manufacture, but sometimes to make better use of the of the PCB size I want to create panels that are the minimum size I need to pay for with JLCPCB who I frequently use to make these boards. Another problem I have found when doing respins of boards that have problems or errors, is keeping track of different versions, while i have tried in the past to keep up with a version on the board this hasn&amp;rsquo;t always worked out, so for these boards I wanted to add reference to the git version used to generate the files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infrared Sensor with an LED Matrix</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/ir_hub75/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/ir_hub75/</guid>
      <description>Having picked up a couple of LED Matrix&amp;rsquo;s from aliexpress that I thought should finally be put to some good use, having perviously made up some IR Thermal camera PMods I thought it would be a great idea to hook them up together, and have a nice big display with the array from these sensors scaled up.
The hardware that is needed mostly relies on what I had already built, mainly the RP2040 PMod Board and the PMod IR Camera, but there is the need for a board to interface between the HUB75 display and the RP2040 PMod board.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading the christmas countdown with GPS</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/chrismas_gps_countdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/chrismas_gps_countdown/</guid>
      <description>The countdown timer that I created last year, which used my custom RP2040 Pmod board with the PMod Severn Segment Display I had also created, was in need of an upgrade. The main aim of this project was to replace the Raspberry Pi Zero that provided the time data to what was just a display made of my custom hardware, and turn it into something that can run automonously, by getting that time data from a GPS reveiver.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a GPS PMod Board</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/gps_pmod_board/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/gps_pmod_board/</guid>
      <description>I have been looking to put together a GPS board for a while, as I had a few ideas for upgrading a project with realtime time information, and a few things that I could try out if I had location or time data, as well as an accurate timing pulse source. While there are actually plenty of options for just buying a pre-made PMod module, I decided I would be better of giving it a go myself as I wanted a few of them and that could make it cheaper to build my own if I needed a few.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started IKEA Vindriktning in Home Assistant with Pico W</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/ikea-air_quality-sensor/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/ikea-air_quality-sensor/</guid>
      <description>The IKEA Vindriktning is an air quality sensor sold for just £13, that makes use of a PM1006 sensor inside to detect particle matter in the air. Normally the readins from the sensor are displayed on one of 3 LED&amp;rsquo;s on the front of the unit, but here we are looking to collect this data and add it into Home Assistant .
There are a large number of posts and instructions avalible online for modifying the IKEA Vindriktning or removing the PM1006 sensor and building a Home Assistant integrated sensor using an ECP32 module.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RP2040 PMod PCB</title>
      <link>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/rp2040_pmod/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jjhorton.co.uk/posts/rp2040_pmod/</guid>
      <description>Having perviously built myself a Pico PMod Board around the Raspberry Pi Pico, I wanted to take this to the next level, and build myself a few boards from scratch. So once the orders went live for the RP2040 microcontroller a few months ago, I ordered some, and then did nothing with them for a while.
Like many people, I seem to end up with more ideas than time and it took me a little while to get around to this one.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
